hello so this is Eric trying to get in
my 10,000 steps nowhere to talk to you
guys about some difficult issues because
I'm seeing stuff that there's no
question that I have no choice I would
love to be remaining silent right now
and there's no way shape or form
there's no I have no option but to speak
because this is getting really dangerous
and I'm talking about the calls to
defund the police that I'm seeing with
respect to the mayor of Minneapolis
being shamed in front of a crowd and let
me begin by saying that I don't think
that white Americans us whether you
consider Jews white or not is another
question for another day understand
enough about the black American
experience and where all of this is
coming from and so I wanted to get into
the history because I think there's some
surprises and twists and turns the first
thing that we don't talk enough about is
lynching we talk about it maybe we use
the word lynching but we don't actually
look at what lynching was or is there
were nearly 5,000 people
I believe lynched officially in the
United States of America during the peak
years of the phenomena and I want to
talk about the humiliation of lynching I
want to talk about something that many
of you don't know about weirdly which is
lynching postcards and souvenirs from
lynchings and the utter barbarity and
savagery of the American experience as
regards II as regards extrajudicial
torture and killing of the most graphic
and vile cond and the reason we don't
talk about it is it includes things like
people being castrated in front of a
crowd and being fed their own testicles
and so understandably everybody is
incredibly squeamish to talk about the
barbarism of lynching and in many ways
this is animating our current discussion
again if you don't like the shakiness of
the camera
just you can listen to my voice I'm just
doing this to walk but we don't really
understand fully the terror of lynching
and we don't understand what the black
community's been through bluntly
furthermore we don't understand the
prevalence of certain techniques that
swelled our jails for example I want you
to look up throw down weapons or throw
away weapons or throw away gun to throw
down gun on policing blogs which discuss
how to plant an untraceable weapon at
the scene of a crime where and something
goes wrong the terror that many African
Americans experience is is that they are
in a some situation without recourse
where evidence can be planted where
hatred can cause them to be completely
vulnerable to the awesome power of the
state and because white and black
America have different intellectual
traditions because the black church was
incredibly important in as an alternate
channel of information all of this
I think contributes I would like you
guys to listen to the strong strange
fruit as sung by Billie Holiday which
was called the song of the century some
people say it's over the rainbow but it
has been called the song of the 20th
century that song the strange fruit of
course our black men predominantly
twisting underneath the tree so I want
to say that for many people have never
heard of a throwaway gun or a throw down
gun who've never understood what a
lynching postcard is and the sort of
just the openness in them of the
barbarity that we've displayed towards
our own people our african-american
brothers and sisters a lot of this stuff
doesn't make sense because this is
playing in to the
a sadistic and psychosexual nightmare
because if tell me that there isn't
something about castrating a person to
display for all the world and showing
that you have so little fear that you're
going to send an open postcard in the
mail that is what I've called message
violence and you're seeing it and that
has to do with why the cop has his hand
in his pocket
from the perspective of why that killing
looks so horrible it's the casual and
indifferent nature of the potential
angle that the racial aspect could have
this is effectively looks like a trophy
hunter posing with this kill alright so
get that all in your head get amped up
pissed off angry ok that's also not the
whole fucking story and this new call to
defund the police is completely bananas
dangerous and insane police need to be
funded or whatever level the police need
to be funded at and the idea of
abolishing the police is madness and I'm
starting to hear that and there's a key
issue about whether blacks and whites
and Jews and everybody are equal in this
in this world or not ok well if my black
brother and sister are not equal then I
will spend my time saying no no no of
course we have to understand their
plight completely we have to understand
that nobody can understand black and
brown bodies and what it looks like to
be terrorized in your own home Society
right because the awesome power of the
state which is as we have said vapors
theory is that it is a monopoly on
violence and so when you believe that
you have a state that is monopolizing
violence against you you're not equal in
some sense you have a moral claim to
superiority that you have been through
something that others have not that you
have a history and that hat that history
stretches all the way back to the 1600s
and the
pain of the slave is the pain of today
and there is no dissipation because of
the humiliation of that process and I
think that there is something to that
but let's talk about equality if you're
really equal I can tell you when you're
out of control
that's my brother not as the other not
as you people but as my fellow right and
as my brother you're out of control
calling for the defunding or the
abolition of the police for it because
you have decided that the reason that
this is taking off in this way is 100%
because of police brutality and racism
first of all it's not even true because
I've been talking about this crisis for
years long before George Floyd was ever
killed by this cop all right this was
gonna come no matter what you can check
off but I've been boring people
following my feet silly saying you know
this thing is about to come unraveled
and of course it's becoming unraveled
and it's becoming unraveled not because
of the catalyst but because of the
environment that was supersaturated
before George Floyd was presumably
murdered in broad daylight in front of
his fellow citizens by this cop and
maybe in that group of cops when nobody
did anything okay
well you remember that song strange
fruit that song was not written by
Billie Holiday it wasn't even written by
a black man
or a black woman who was written by a
Jew named Abel Meeropol a novel mere
Poole was such a badass and we try not
to get emotional here that when the
entire world decided to kill both of the
parents of the rosenberg children in
1953 through electrocution i believe its
singsing the family wouldn't even take
the children that's how powerful a mob
is everyone was afraid to be associated
with the Rosenbergs almost everyone I
should say because Abba mayor pol was
not afraid and he took the kids in as
his own
and that is Jewish stuff there are a lot
of Jewish cowards there are a lot of
Jewish weaklings but you'll remember the
scene I think in one of the Avengers
movies where the Loki character is ready
to execute anyone who won't kneel and
one guy stands up and I guarantee you
that was an attempt at a Yiddish accent
so it is in part the job of the Jews not
to go along with the crowd and the crowd
is out of control the crowd that smashes
glass is not only letting the white man
know that violence is on tap because of
the brutality which I started this
broadcast talking about has to be
addressed that broken glass sounds like
Cristal not to every goddamn Jew in the
world and the violence of the state I
should point out that you would think
that 100% of the people lynched in the
United States were black the
overwhelming number seventy five percent
around were black but about a quarter of
them were white some of them Jews and
monopolizing the problem of police
brutality making the assumption that
this was a you know targeted killing
just about race that the pre-existing
conditions didn't I mean look this guy
who killed this guy murdered probably I
don't need to prostrate myself in front
of you and let you know that of course
that's wrong because everybody knows
it's wrong I don't know anybody who's
stood up for this okay
the problem that we have now is critical
feeling and critical thinking if you
want to tell me that slavery is such a
problem and it's still a problem how are
you going to make the argument that the
Holocaust that happened within living
memory is a less significant event
how are you going to make the argument
that what is it 1.1 million Jewish
children were murdered children murdered
industrially okay and you want to stand
down the what you want to stand down the
police you want to take away the people
that I can call when a Jewish school is
threatened you want to defund the people
who I would call to stop a shooter like
in Squirrel Hill and in Pittsburgh what
right do you have why do you think
everything is about you it's this is not
all about the Jews this is not all about
Americans this is a worldwide thing
that's going up in flames and right now
we have a situation that some of us have
been talking about it for ages long
before George when George Floyd was
walking around fine and now this is all
about black lives matter which by the
way has a very serious Jewish issue
where they've called for Israel to be
treated as a genocide I'll state
whatever Israel's problems are with
Palestinian Arabs look this is the
problem of critical feeling we talk
about critical thinking having your own
thoughts thinking from first principles
critical feeling is making sure that you
don't get caught up in the feelings of
other people the feelings that are meant
to coerce you that are meant to divorce
you from reason from rationality from
doing the right thing and quite honestly
I've always wanted to know in a
difficult situation whether I was mere
pol strong you know could I write like
he wrote to take care of my black
brothers and sisters you know I don't
think we've talked very much about I've
talked about it once in public at a
private event at the Ice House in
Pasadena but there was a place in
Pasadena very close to the comedy club
that I did my first live show at where I
was in charge of it which I think in the
1920s had something called International
Day it was a public swimming pool that
allowed blacks to swim for one day
where they change the water and my
family said f that alright that was part
of our radicalization to the American
left which was that we just hated the
idea that you'd come up with some day
called International Day where blacks
could use the water so that the whites
would contaminate look we've been at
this a long time as a result of having
been here for around a hundred years I
don't feel like guilt about this I don't
feel like oh my god I never knew there
was a real problem of course I've known
there's a real problem we've been active
in this thing for forever and when you
tried to stand down the police at
Evergreen State College when they were
looking for my brother with baseball
bats
that's how deeply disturbed the American
left in its kind of bizarre metastatic
progressive Incan incarnation has become
so what I'm going to say to you guys is
it's extremely important to first of all
understand the depths of the problem on
the black side of the equation because
lord knows I don't think it's being
explained properly in concepts like
lynching postcards and throw away
weapons are extremely important so let's
all do our homework and on the other
hand this is not to be monopolized like
this our whole system has been falling
apart and everybody's angry women are
angry black people are angry poor people
are angry professionals are angry the
number of people who aren't really angry
is very small and quite honestly lots of
us who have looked at black live matters
you know positions or if heard calls
that white people should will their
houses to black people or you know I'm
giving rides to black people I'm giving
food to black people Jesus it's okay to
take care of your community to some
extent but some part of this is going
metastatic and it is destroying an
American experiment in righting the
wrongs that's been underway as if
nothing has been moving as if nothing
has been happening and so this is
obviously a really dangerous time to
stand up and say this but to defund the
police is to put other communities at
risk
and quite honestly you're not the whole
story I don't even think this is mostly
happening because this because of racism
yes we've had a problem with racist
policing for a long time but it's a lot
better than it used to be and if I
recall correctly when the New York New
Orleans Police Department was out of
control the guy who came up to clean it
up the first thing he did was to raise
salaries so people had something to lose
who had some dignity right so my point
to you is I want you to think about the
following question when you defund the
police or abolish the police you know of
course if they're if they're getting too
much money then that's a different
question but if the question is that we
should basically starve the police so
that there can be less policing I
guarantee you that when you've got some
white supremacists walking around with
guns people are gonna say where's the
police right because what we're doing is
lurching from one position to another
we were lurching from everybody has to
get inside because of kovat and we go
right to what oh my god white supremacy
is the real public health issue Jesus
Christ really I mean is anybody that
dumb to be able to do that without
whiplash until actually I can't even
imagine it so what I'm trying to say is
it is absolutely the case that many of
us need to pay attention to the history
of the other I think we need to pay
attention to Armenian history but you
know one of the reasons that in my
opinion Jews don't win the oppression
Olympics is because in general we were
smart enough to realize that that wasn't
our ticket we have to talk about it
because we're all screwed up about it
we're all screwed up about Cristal not
all of us were all screwed up because of
the photographs of a soldier you know
pointing a gun at a mother with her
child of seeing piles of bodies
if you've you've ever been to Babi Yar
in Kiev I think I was physically sick
just being there right you're not the
only people with trauma
everybody's got trauma
everybody's got fear and defunding the
police is the most dangerous crazy idea
to the point of abolition that this
radical left contingent has and trying
to shame people so that they say oh I
looked deep inside myself and you know I
looked at my own bigotry and in print
look we've all got some bigotry and
Prejudice certainly black America has
bigotry and Prejudice believe me right
but the other thing is is that we all
have inconsistent natures yeah one
moment we're bigoted the other moment
we're helping somebody out it looks
nothing like us we've got a look and
interrogate our own national identity
and national soul at a completely
different level and what I wanted to say
is we've got to bring this thing in for
the best crash landing we can walk away
from without having a situation in which
a an organization with anti-semitic
roots is calling for a defunding of the
police often to the point of abolition
and shaming others who won't stand up
because it's really frightening to stand
up at the right moment and this is the
right moment this is the moment where
effectively the majority of one one
against the many anybody who can pass
the Asch conformity test the Stanford
Prison Experiment and the Milgram
experiment is needed in leadership and
not almost any of our leadership to do
it look up russell Feingold from the
neighboring state of Wisconsin as the
one member of the Senate who in the time
of maximal panic after 9/11 voted
against the Patriot Act right now we're
in a situation where the mob and our
feelings because we all feel oh shit if
I don't go along with the mob
what does that make me I'm seeing
beautiful pictures of people holding
hands and kneeling and praying together
I'm also seeing pictures of people
breaking into windows it's stealing
everything in the store right lots of
things are going on but they're going on
for all of us and as much as I care
about Jewish issues and remind you about
Jewish issues this isn't just about Jews
it's about the fact that we have a
shared future shared history
and we know each other and we know that
defunding the police to get rid of a
some problem right to get rid of some
issue with racism where we don't know
how big it is because we don't know how
to condition the variables and to figure
out what the excess use of force against
different groups is exactly but things
have gotten a hell of a lot better from
the old days
and we are somehow stuck in some past an
imagined past where maybe five million
were lynched rather than five thousand
and maybe all of them were black and
they weren't and maybe we're in a
situation in which if you really think
about it what was it six million out of
nine point five million jews and who are
living in europe were killed in this
mechanistic adventure we call the
holocaust or the Shoah so if we're gonna
talk about you know some sort of basis
for morality i just want to say
something every Passover we sing Paul
Robeson's famous song go down Moses
we're so honored that Harriet Tubman
would take the name Moses from our
tradition because this story about
escape from slavery is one of the most
important stories in the world and you
know quite honestly I've been in love
with black culture since I was a kid not
because of a sense of guilt but because
of a sense of awe and envy that a group
of people imported as labor would turn
out to be such a genius based community
I think about the invention of America's
classical music known as jazz by
effectively Louis Armstrong in its
modern incarnation in the late 20s and I
just think Jesus how could anybody be
that brilliant you know or Art Tatum at
the piano whatever it is the comedy that
lifted us up the strength and the
courage of Dick Gregory
my personal hero and I can't stand
there's nobody out here who will stand
up and say what needs to be said which
is yeah we have a problem with racism
and policing this was a particularly
picturesque incident no we don't know
exactly what happened inferentially we
feel that it's very clear this was a
bigot but we went that way with
covington right and how did that work
out
right we have to get in control of our
feelings so what I'm gonna say to you
guys is practice critical feeling which
is having your own feelings try to feel
from first principles not only think for
in first principles and you know just
somebody has somebody says you're
overthinking this
right now you're over feeling this we
have a right to be mad and we have a
right to channel that as Americans we
have a right to equality and part of
equality is saying brother you're out of
control
yep something bad really really bad
happened but we are not going to defund
the police to the point of abolishing
them and you're not the only community
here and you're not the only person
who's ever suffered police brutality and
there is nobody in the country who
doesn't fear the police when they pull
them over and the guy's got a gun and
it's a rainy night nobody knows what can
happen next
so it's not the case that White's skin
is in some sense an insurance policy
against something going wrong so I think
it's really important to channel the
positive energy that's coming off of our
streets in a positive way that works for
all communities but I'm going to ask you
when you've got a white supremacists
shooting up is some sort of an apartment
complex or a mall or whatever what are
you gonna call your gonna call the
police
when you see people defacing a Jewish
school who are you gonna call you're
gonna call the police
we're asking the police to do all this
work for us and to decide that one
community's interpretation of events is
sufficient and that we are also guilty
that we should simply stand down
the one the thin line we have between
Anarchy and civilization I'm sorry no
and I'm sorry that there aren't any
grown-ups here to say no but the answer
is no and the answer is no because there
are other communities that can easily
compete with your claims on oppression
historically and those police are
incredibly important to those
communities
so please think once think twice think
three times before this idea and for
those of you who understand this
intuitively you have the reverse
homework assignment don't look up
lynching postcards try not to make
yourself sick because I have to tell you
that it's not enough to intellectualize
this you've got to feel the helplessness
the vulnerability and just feeling the
loss of integrity and not being able to
keep yourself or your family safe it is
absolutely an incredible experience to
see what we did to our own people and
where the the horror it may have been a
very may have been less than 5,000
people lynched in this fashion but until
you actually put yourself in the
situation of message violence with who
can you call you know the old the old
song 911 one is a joke right we've been
very focused and frightened on the idea
that not everybody has equal access to
policing we have to do better on
policing what we cannot do is get rid of
policing and I'm sorry you know I
understand their idea police can be
rhesus so let's get rid of the police
but we saw this at Evergreen and we saw
an actual college president stand down
his own security force his own police
force on campus while people were going
around with baseball bats hunting don't
do it it may be a beautiful sounding
idea but you're opening the gates of
Hell and the fact that you had good in
your heart when you were doing it is no
defense we all know better so this was a
tough one I didn't enjoy doing this one
but I love you all and and I love you
enough to tell you the truth I think we
are equal and one of the things that
comes from equality is that I can say
this is a stupid fucking idea and you've
had better ones I can try to ask you to
remind yourself that a lot of us count
on the police black families black lives
black and brown bodies as you like to
say included love you
I'm gonna go over to Instagram and maybe
do some Q&A at Eric our Weinstein so if
you want to tell me that I'm completely
off-base I will take your call be well
in Shavua Tov